Hi, I'm Chris Faircloth, Artistic Director and co-owner of Salon Teez.
One of the fringes that is wildly popular right now is the side swept fringe, where it goes from short to long across the face.
We could create this just by placing our comb in a position such as this and cutting the hair off but an easy way to do this would be to place our comb on the hair line and rock the comb back.
Now we'll look to see where the part or the section is going to be and rather than create another pyramid line down to the corner of the eyebrow, we'll actually incorporate that part into our section here, so our section will be more of a slight rectangle than a true pyramid.
Once I have the length of where I want that hair to be, I'll simply cut the ends of the hair off, and this may take more than one cut.
Now I've created my fringe.
I simply comb the hair back over and I've created a nice short to longer piece.
You can create this or do this as short as you want to.
It's best to do it in increments versus just one big large chunk; otherwise it may be shorter than what you actually wanted it to be.
So again, I comb the hair over, have it nice and tight, I'm down to a horizontal, slightly twist the hair over, grab it with my fingers, notice that where my shortest piece will be is about at the bridge of the nose, cut the hair off bluntly, release the hair and comb it back over the side that we want it to go on.
And now I've got my short to long piece that melds into the sides and the back nicely without creating a lot of havoc.